Frances Densmore papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Frances Densmore papers 1883-1957
AFC 1944/002
Densmore, Frances
3,786 items
23 containers
12 linear feet
9 scrapbooks
11 boxes (9,500 pages)
76 lantern slides
19 glass negatives
5 photographic prints: black-and-white
1 photograph: black-and-white, phonodeik; 38 feet
1 drawing: birchbark
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Field notebooks, correspondence, lecture notes, manuscripts, scrapbooks, as well as visual material in photographic prints, lantern glass slides and glass plate negatives related to Frances Densmore's collection of Native American music and culture. The materials span 1883 to 1957. The papers include inventories of hundreds of recordings Densmore made over fifty years of studying and preserving American Indian music. The collection includes reprints of Densmore's publications, as well as writings by others. Also included in the collection is a "phonodeik" (a photographic visualization of sound) by Dayton C. Miller and a Chippewa birchbark drawing.
Provenance
Frances Densmore; 1944. This collection developed at the American Folklife Center as a gradual accumulation of material related to Frances Densmore from various sources rather than as a discrete accrual donated by Densmore. As a result, the materials represented in this collection are a combination of traditional collections material and subject file materials related to Densmore.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Sound recordings created by Frances Densmore can be found in many separate collections at the American Folklife Center. For associated sound recordings currently listed in the catalog see Frances Densmore field recordings collections:
AFC 1943/018 (Chippewa)
AFC 1943/024 (Sioux and Navajo)
AFC 1943/025 (Miscellaneous)
AFC 1948/069 (Menominee)
AFC 1948/070 (Iroquois)
AFC 1948/073 (Winnebago)
AFC 1948/075 (Alabama)
AFC 1948/077 (Choctaw)
AFC 1948/078 (Seminole and Calusa)
AFC 1948/080 (Teton and Santee Sioux)
AFC 1948/118 (Pawnee)
AFC 1948/121 (Northern Ute)
AFC 1948/122 (Mandan and Hidatsa)
AFC 1948/126 (Quileute)
AFC 1948/131 (Papago)
AFC 1948/132 (Makah)
AFC 1948/133 (Quechan)
AFC 1948/134 (Yaqui)
AFC 1948/135 (Cocopa)
AFC 1948/136 (Clayoquot)
AFC 1948/137 (Mohave)
AFC 1948/138 (Omaha)
AFC 1948/139 (Santo Domingo Pueblo)
AFC 1948/140 (Cheyenne)
AFC 1948/142 (Acoma Pueblo)
AFC 1948/143 (Cochiti Pueblo)
AFC 1948/144 (Isleta Pueblo)
AFC 1948/145 (Cuna)
AFC 1948/147 (Chilliwack, British Columbia)
AFC 1948/148 (Zuni)
AFC 1948/149 (Unidentified)
AFC 1969/026 (Winnebago)
AFC 1983/035 (Mandan and Hidatsa)
Access and Restrictions
The Frances Densmore papers are open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Frances Densmore (1867-1957) was an American ethnomusicologist known for her studies of Native American music and culture. During the early part of the twentieth century, she worked as a music teacher with Native Americans nationwide, while also learning, recording, and transcribing Native American music, and documenting its use in culture. She helped preserve Native American culture in a time when government policy was to encourage Native Americans to adopt Western customs. Densmore began recording music officially for the Smithsonian Institution's Bureau of American Ethnology (BAE) in 1907. In her fifty-plus years of studying and preserving American Indian music, she collected thousands of recordings. Many of the recordings she made on behalf of the BAE are now held in the Library of Congress. While her original recordings often were on wax cylinders, many of them have been reproduced using other media and are included in other archives. Densmore frequently was published in the journal American Anthropologist, contributing consistently throughout her career.
Scope and Content
The papers of Frances Densmore (1867-1957) span the years 1883 to 1957. The collection documents over fifty years of Densmore's work studying and preserving Native American music. The papers are primarily in English with some materials written in French, Spanish, Russian, Arabic, German, Italian, and Greek.
The collection documents Densmore's work as an ethnomusicologist, including her extensive work learning, recording, transcribing, and documenting the uses of American Indian music. Her papers include field notebooks, correspondence, song lists and indexes, lecture notes, scrapbooks, photographic prints, lantern glass slides, and glass plate negatives relating to her work collecting Native American music and culture. Materials are included from her work with tribes including the Chippewa, the Mandan, Hidatsa, the Sioux, the northern Pawnee of Oklahoma, the Papago (Tohono O'odham) of Arizona, American Indians of Washington and British Columbia, Winnebago and Menominee of Wisconsin, Pueblo Indians of the Southwest, the Seminoles of Florida, and the Kuna Indians of Panama. Also included in this collection are Densmore's publications and publications sent to her by anthropologists prominent in the field, a phonodeik (a photographic visualization of sound) by Dayton C. Miller, and a Chippewa birchbark drawing.
Arrangement
The Frances Densmore papers are organized in eleven series:
Series 1: Collection documentation
Series 2: Lists and commentary
Series 3: Correspondence
Series 4: Field notes, publications, and miscellany
Series 5: "Reprints" [smaller Densmore publications]
Series 6: Lectures and presentations
Series 7: Miscellany and German pamphlets
Series 8: Publications by others
Series 9: American Indian-related publications by others
Series 10: Scrapbook and miscellany
Series 11: Photographs
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Densmore, Frances, 1867-1957
Organizations
Federal Cylinder Project (U.S.)
Subjects
Cylinder recordings.; Ethnomusicology.; Field recordings.; Indians of North America--Music.; Ojibwa art.; Ojibwa Indians.; Songs--Texts.; Sound recordings--Collectors and collecting.
Form/Genre
Articles.; Correspondence.; Field notes.; Lectures.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Song texts.; Translations.
Container List
- Series 1: Collection documentation
  - Original box numbers/re-boxed listings, 1987, 2003 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Conservation Division treatment of bark drawing: Photographic documentation (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Glass slide rehousing and digitization, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Series 2: Lists and commentary
  - Ring binder 1-Chippewa (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Ring binder 1-Sioux (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Ring binder 2-Pawnee (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Ring binder 2-Ute (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Ring binder 2-Mandan and Hidatsa (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Ring binder 3-Papago, May 21, 1955 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Ring binder 4-Yuma, Cocopa, Yaqui (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Ring binder 5-Menominee, September 14, 1950 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Ring binder 5-Tule (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Ring binder 5-British Columbia (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Ring binder 6-Alaska (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Ring binder 6-Acoma (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Ring binder 6-Winnebago (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Acoma song lists (and other Pueblas), 1929-1931 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Makah song lists (also Nitinat, Clayoquot, Quileute), 1923-1928 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Menominee song lists, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Pawnee song lists, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Seminole and Calusa song lists, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Winnebago song lists, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Handbook of the Smithsonian-Densmore Collection of American Indian Sound Recordings in the National Archives pages 1-90, 1943 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Handbook of the Smithsonian-Densmore Collection of American Indian Sound Recordings in the National Archives pages 91-180, 1943 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Handbook of the Smithsonian-Densmore Collection of American Indian Sound Recordings in the National Archives pages 181-270, 1943 (Box-folder 2/22)
- Series 3: Correspondence
  - Correspondence with Bureau of American Ethnology staff, 1927-1933 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1924-1940 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1948 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1949 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1950 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1951 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Correspondence with library staff, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 3/10)
- Series 4: Field notes, publications, and miscellany
  - Chronology of the Study and Presentation of Indian Music, 1893-1944 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Miscellany, 1903, 1930-1937 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Draft of letter to Bruno Nettl (Box-folder 4/3)
  - List of cylinder records (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Bibliography (carbon copy) (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Field notebook - Chippewa, 1909 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - C.E. Seashore's assessment of Frances Densmore's hearing ability, 1914 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Music of Santo Domingo Pueblo, 1938 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Forms Frances Densmore used for melodic analysis, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Correspondence and annotations, 1908, 1924-1936 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Publishing plans and press notices, 1926 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Cheyenne and Arapaho Music, 1936 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Choctaw Music, 1943 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Music of the Indians of British Columbia, 1943 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Music of the Tule Indians of Panama, 1926 (Box-folder 4/15)
- Series 5: "Reprints" [smaller Densmore publications]
  - Inventory of reprints (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Reprints number 1, 1906-1923 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Reprints number 2, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Reprints number 3, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Reprints number 4, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Reprints number 5, 1938-1948 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Reprints number 6, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 5/7)
- Series 6: Lectures and presentations
  - Drafts of papers and lectures (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Lecture circulars, 1899-1904, 1933 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Manuscript of A Lecture on Indian Music, circa 1895- circa 1898 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Paper- A Cycle of Indian Songs, 1905 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Lecture- The Music of the American Indians, Anthropological Society of Washington, April 27, 1909 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Lecture- Chippewa Music, Anthropological Society of Washington, April, 1911 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Lecture- The Sioux Sun Dance, Anthropological Society of Washington, April, 1913 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Lecture- Sioux Music, Anthropological Society of Washington, February 3, 1914 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Lecture- Mandan Music, Anthropological Society of Washington, March 21, 1916 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Lecture delivered at two high schools in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, October 2, 1923 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Radio Address- Indian Music, WCCO, Minneapolis, Minnesota, January 30, 1927 (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Lecture-Institute of Arts, Minneapolis, Minnesota, February 21, 1928 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Paper- Some Results of the Study of Indian Music, Academy of Athens, Athens, Greece, 1928 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Address- Indian Women, College Women's Club, Red Wing, Minnesota, March 5, 1928 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Lecture for Woman's Club, Minneapolis, Minnesota, January 16, 1934 (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Series of talks on radio station WCCO, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1932 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Lecture- Music in the Treatment of the Sick by American Indians, Mayo Foundation, Rochester, Minnesota, December 14, 1934 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Lecture- Indian Singers and Their Songs, University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa, February 8, 1934 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Lecture- The Music of the American Indian, 1934 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Lecture- Indian Music, Minot, North Dakota, April 23, 1925 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Paper- Regional Peculiarities of Indian Songs, American Association for the Advancement of Science, Minneapolis, Minnesota, June 28, 1935 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Paper- Methods of Recording Indian Songs, American Association for the Advancement of Science, St. Louis, Missouri, January 1936 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Address- Indian Music, National Folk Festival, Chicago, Illinois, May 24, 1937 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Lecture- Medicinal Uses of Plants by the American Indians, National Association of Pharmacists meeting, Minneapolis, Minnesota, August 18, 1938 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Paper- The Native Art of the Chippewa Indians, Central States Branch, American Anthropological Association, Minneapolis, Minnesota, May 8, 1941 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Address- The Music of the American Indians for a church organization in Red Wing, Minnesota, February 23, 1945 (Box-folder 6/26)
- Series 7: Miscellany and German pamphlets
  - Cyrillic and Arabic song transcriptions and harmonizations (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Notes on Bureau of American Ethnology pages (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Photocopy of C.E. Seashore's list of musical ability of Frances Densmore, 1914 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Miscellany 1 (List of lectures, papers, and addresses), circa 1899-1945 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Index of miscellany (Items 1-23), 1945 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Miscellany 2-6, 1906, 1944-1945, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Miscellany 7 (Letter to sister about working with the Ute), 1914 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Miscellany 9-14, 1917, 1924, 1932-1934, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Miscellany 15-19, 1917, 1939-1945 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Miscellany 20 (Two German reviews of Chippewa Music ), 1911 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Miscellany 21 (Illustrated clipping from Talking Machine World ), circa 1909 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Miscellany 22 (Scenario to Musical Pictures of Chippewa Indian Life ), 1917 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Miscellany 23 (Correspondence to Frances Densmore regarding her work), 1930-1944 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - List of pamphlets in German (Box-folder 7/15)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (1 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (2 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/17)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (3 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (4 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (5 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - German pamphlets by Erich M. von Hornbostel (6 of 6), 1905-1911, 1924-1938 (Box-folder 7/21)
- Series 8: Publications by others
  - Publication announcement, 1934 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Ethno-Musicology newsletter, numbers 1 and 2 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - The Masterkey Volume 30, number 2, 1956 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Publications received-Andersen, Arthur Olaf, 1935 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Publications received-Berliner, Emile, 1894 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Publications received-Frederick, H., et al., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Publications received-Giuffrida-Ruggeri, V., 1918 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Publications received-Herzog, George, 1930-1936 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Publications received-Hornbostel, E.M. von (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Publications received-Johnson, Guy B., 1931 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Publications received-Maltezos, Constantine, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Publications received-Myers, Charles H., 1905 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Publications received-Rigg, Melvin Gillison, 1942 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Publications received-Scripture, E.W., 1905 (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Publications received-Seashore, C.E., 1920 (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Publications received-Shambaugh, George E., 1908 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Publications received-Sunaga, Katsumi, 1936 (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Publications received-Teubner, Faatui and Ernest W. (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Publications received-Wead, Charles Kasson, 1900, 1910 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Publications received-Williams, C.F. Abdy (Box-folder 8/20)
- Series 9: American Indian-related publications by others
  - American Indian material-Bloch, Ernest, 1928 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - American Indian material-Cresson, H.T., 1883 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - American Indian material-Fillmore, John Comfort, 1899 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - American Indian material-Fletcher, Alice C., 1915 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - American Indian material-Gustaver, 1923 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - American Indian material-Hague, Eleanor, 1915 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - American Indian material-Herzog, George (1 of 2), 1926-1935 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - American Indian material-Herzog, George (2 of 2), 1936 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - American Indian material-Herzog and Linton, 1935 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - American Indian material-Humphrey, Reverend William Brewster, 1911 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - American Indian material-Kanhere, S.G., 1926 (Box-folder 9/11)
  - American Indian material-Lachmann, Robert, 1929 (Box-folder 9/12)
  - American Indian material-Lawson, Robert Campbell, 1926 (Box-folder 9/13)
  - American Indian material-Loring, Harold, 1906 (Box-folder 9/14)
  - American Indian material-Rhodes, Willard, 1943 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - American Indian material-Roberts, Helen and Haeberlin, Herman, 1918 (Box-folder 9/16)
  - American Indian material-Swanton, John (Box-folder 9/17)
  - American Indian material-Titus, Maude Essex, 1920 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - American Indian material-Watt, Henry O., 1924 (Box-folder 9/19)
  - American Indian material-Sargeant, Winthrop (Box-folder 9/20)
- Series 10: Scrapbooks and miscellany
  - Original housings for photographic materials (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Miscellany 8 (two photographs), 1924, 1940, 1 black-and-white photographic print (5x7 inch); 1 black-and-white photographic print (8x10 inch) (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Photographs, 1912-1917, 1949, Portraits of Frances Densmore; 2 black-and-white photographic prints (5x7 inch); 1 black-and-white photographic print (8x10 inch) (Box-folder 10/3)
  - One paper item (mounted), 1907, Contains a photocopy of the original drawing in Box-Folder 10/4 as well as a typed description of the item. (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Drawing-Gay-me-wun-aush, 1907, Original drawing of six songs of the Chippewa created by Gay-me-wun-aush. The songs are numbers 103, 104, 105, 106, and 107 on pages 114-115 in the Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45 (the fifth song is omitted).; Gay-me-wun-aush (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Chippewa birchbark drawing, Birchbark drawing depicting a Chippewa mnemonic.; 1 birchbark drawing (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Phonodeik photograph of Ute woman's dance, 1917, Dayton C. Miller; 1 black-and-white phonodeik photographic print (38 feet)
  - Typed slip accompanying Ute woman's dance (phonodeik) (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Dayton C. Miller inventory of material sent to Frances Densmore (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Dayton C. Miller manuscripts, 1916-1927 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Scrapbook #1, 1889-1900 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook #2, 1901-1911 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook #3, 1911-1926 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook #4, 1927-1929 (Box 18)
  - Scrapbook #5, 1930-1933 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook #6, 1934-1938 (Box 20)
  - Scrapbook #7, 1939-1949 (Box 21)
  - Scrapbook #8, 1949-1954 (Box 22)
  - Oversize newsclippings from scrapbook #8 and #9, 1949-1954, Newsclippings from scrapbook #8 include: "Dr. Densmore," Minneapolis Star and "Red Wing Woman to be Awarded Citation," Daily Republican. Newsclippings from scrapbook #9 include: "More Facts About Indians," Newark Evening News. (Oversize folder OS01)
  - Scrapbook #9, 1954-1957 (Box 23)
- Series 11: Photographs, All photograph titles were composed by Judith Gray, based on her research.; All digital files for Series 11 can be found within the same digital object identifier: afc1944002.
  - Subseries 1: Lantern slides, Slides AFC1944/002: PH001 to PH050 were used by Frances Densmore in a lecture in Minot, South Dakota in 1935.
    - Lake in Minnesota or Wisconsin (white birches), AFC 1944/002: PH001; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Same scene as AFC 1944/002: PH051 (Box 12)
    - Bark-covered lodge, unfamiliar-style hand drum, location unidentified, though northern, AFC 1944/002: PH002; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Gemiwunac, Sept.-Oct. 1907 (Chippewa singer from Leech Lake, Minnesota), reverse of Plate 9, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45 (Chippewa Music), September - October 1907, AFC 1944/002: PH003; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Version of AFC 1944/002: PH083 (Box 12)
    - Chippewa Midewiwin song mnemonics (songs 103-104, 106-107 on pages 114-115, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45), AFC 1944/002: PH004; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Same as AFC 1944/002: PH085 (Box 12)
    - Love-Charm Song page 91 in Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 45, AFC 1944/002: PH005; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH078 (Box 12)
    - Possibly painted council tent at Bull Head, South Dakota (see different view on Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 72), AFC 1944/002: PH006; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Same as AFC 1944/002: PH069 (Box 12)
    - Shuffling-feet dance (Standing Rock Sioux), different view from Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 78, AFC 1944/002: PH007; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Same as AFC 1944/002: PH067 (Box 12)
    - Shuffling-feet dance song transcription, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, page 478, AFC 1944/002: PH008; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH082 (Box 12)
    - Unidentified, AFC 1944/002: PH009; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Unidentified, AFC 1944/002: PH010; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - White-Buffalo-Walking (Teton Sioux), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 11, AFC 1944/002: PH011; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH092 (Box 12)
    - Buffalo Boy (Santee-Yanktonai man), similar to Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 9 (see also page 91), AFC 1944/002: PH012; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH088 (Box 12)
    - Siyaka (Yanktonai-Teton), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 1, AFC 1944/002: PH013; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH089 (Box 12)
    - Possibly Mrs. Good Eagle (Pawnee), see Plate 2c in Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 93 (opposite page 1), AFC 1944/002: PH014; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Brave Buffalo (Standing Rock Sioux singer), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 25, AFC 1944/002: PH015; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH080 (Box 12)
    - Eagle Shield (Standing Rock Sioux singer), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 40, AFC 1944/002: PH016; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH081 (Box 12)
    - Eagle Shield capturing Assiniboin woman (his drawing), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, Plate 65, AFC 1944/002: PH017; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH084 (Box 12)
    - Eagle Shield song transcription, Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 61, page 396, AFC 1944/002: PH018; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Cropped form of AFC 1944/002: PH077 (Box 12)
    - Crow Heart's earth lodge, (Mandan), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 80, Plate 3a], AFC 1944/002: PH019; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)
    - Pan playing on whistle (Hidatsa), Bureau of American Ethnology Bulletin 80, Plate 10a], AFC 1944/002: PH020; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch); Same as AFC 1944/002: PH058 (Box 12)
    - Boats in Neah Bay, Washington, AFC 1944/002: PH021; 1 lantern slide (3.25 x 4 inch) (Box 12)